When you're using Chachi or one of its
competitors, you can get answers that
look like this, where it really feels
like it knows me. Or you can get answers
like this, which would essentially apply
to every single person on this planet.
And today's video, I'll be breaking down
how to get custom answers like the first
one for yourself. And as there's
multiple ways in chatb,
I'll also help you figure out which one
you should be using and how to use it
properly. Your time is valuable, so
let's get right into this. So here's the
deal. Chat has multiple ways of
remembering things about you and
adapting to your preferences. Some are
super simple and some are for
experienced users only. And by the end
of this video, you'll know which one of
these fits your needs and what else is
out there. So, this right here are the
four different ways to customize your
chat experience for yourself. And all
you're going to need for this is a Chat
GBT account. If you're on the free tier,
you have access to memories, custom
instructions, and projects now, too. If
you're on the plus tier or higher, you
also get GPTs. So, first up, let's start
by talking about memories. This is the
easiest way in chat to customize your
experience. In your settings under
personalization, just make sure the
switch is on reference saved memories
and chat will analyze your chats and
remember details about yourself that it
considers important. And one more thing
that I should add about them. When you
have memories turned on, by default, it
will also look back into your other
chats. Just something to be aware of.
You can turn that off here if you only
wanted to be referencing what's inside
of these memories in the future. So,
it's really automatic way of doing this.
But there is a downside to that. Just to
give you a quick demo of this, if I say
something like, "My friends call me the
lawn mower, which side note, they don't.
We just got an email of a AI lawn mower
wanting to sponsor the channel or
something." Thought that was funny. So,
we'll use it as an example here. But if
I tell chat GPT this, there is a chance
that it will save it to my memories. I
can always check by going back to
personalization and checking my
memories. So, it did not add that here.
I could always tell it to manually do
that by saying save this in memories.
And then it will save this to my
memories. So I can manage them from here
and you can see friends call them the
lawn mower. Now it will tell you this
little message but it's quite easy to
forget what is inside of your memories.
And also as I pointed out chat GPD makes
this decision itself. So in this case it
didn't want to save it. In many other
cases it will save details about your
interests, hobbies, your personal life,
your work life. And when I open up a
brand new chat and say something like
write me an Instagram caption for my
next 10 images, you will see that it
writes up different captions. And number
eight here says the lawn mower in full
motion. Now this is very subtle but you
can see that it's clearly using the
nickname and it might also not happen
every single time but as soon as you
have more than one memory in here it
starts infusing those facts into more
and more chats. And if you would be
writing Instagram captions for a
workrelated project you probably
wouldn't want to call yourself the
lawnmower. And this is the downside of
memories. And that's why once you start
using chatdy regularly rather than using
global memories I would strongly
recommend using projects. You can create
a brand new one by saying new project
and then projects allow you to group
chats of a certain type. So I can have
my personal chats in one and my work
rellated chats in another one. This
could be as simple as saying work and
then here under settings I can enable
these projectorimies where it will
automatically gather these details about
me but they will only influence all the
chats within this work project. And
additionally to just these automatically
collected memories here, I can go ahead
and add instructions, which is sort of a
second prompt that is added on top of
everything you send in these project
chats. The same thing goes for files. If
I upload different files here, they will
be added to the context of every
conversation that I start in here. And
ultimately, this is my recommendation on
how to use chat GBT. Set up a work
folder, set up a private folder, and if
you have other projects, feel free to
add more in the future. But splitting
things out is really useful as you can
build out these extra instructions and
add extra files that are only relevant
to your work here. And then if you just
need a neutral chat, just use a new chat
without a project. Another free
alternative to customize your context.
And this is really the first feature
that Chat GBT added to do this are
custom instructions. So you could opt
out of memories and decide to manually
manage your memories. So one way to do
this would be just taking the different
memories that you accumulate over time
and then taking manual control over your
destiny so to say by going to custom
instructions enabling these for new
chats and then these are different
fields that will also be mixed into your
prompt and considered with every new
chat. But here you have full manual
control. It won't automatically add
anything or search for previous chats
for information that could be relevant.
This is very simple. Just what I put in
here that's what it knows and it's
static. So, if I just go down here and
manually paste my memory, now Chachib
also knows that my friends call me in
the lawn mower. Great. So, this is
pretty self-explanatory. It asks what's
your name? What's your profession? But
when it comes to these fields down here,
what trait should chat have? I'll
recommend three each that you could fill
out. One of them is what level of detail
do you want? I saved this preset because
I don't like when Chachib is getting too
wordy. And then you can specify types of
suggestions and critical thinking
levels, creativity levels, and then you
can also specify types of suggestions. I
like to keep things practical, so that's
what I told it here. Down here under
anything else Chachi should know about
you. I find that by far the most useful
thing you can put in here are your
current goals. And that's pretty much
it. The only thing that I didn't cover
here is that you can also pick the
personality of CHP, but I find defaults
to be great. And those are custom
instructions. They're going to apply to
every chat that you open from now on.
And essentially, if we just go back to
the project we created for a second,
this right here is the same thing. So if
you're a new user, probably just start
out with memories. over time turn those
into custom instructions and then over
time move those custom instructions into
your project. That is kind of the
progression you want to go through to
take full control of what chat GBT knows
about you. One important note is that if
I'm opening a brand new chat and I have
both memories and custom instructions
turned on, it will pull from both. If
that's good or bad is situational. It's
just something you need to be aware of.
Otherwise, you'll be writing emails and
it's going to be referring to you as the
lawn mower and you might be confused why
that's the case. And finally, there's
one more thing we need to talk about
here and those are GPTs. And this
confuses many people for good reason
because on the surface GPDs are very
similar to projects. The GPDs are
managed under this tab and then you can
create new GPTs or manage the ones you
have. And as you can see also here you
have these instructions which are
essentially the same thing as custom
instructions or project instructions.
But the difference here is there's a few
more fields. And that's because these
GPTs are essentially a project that are
designed for a specific use case and
that are sharable. So if you're going to
be sharing these, you probably need a
name for them and a description for the
other person to understand what the
purpose of this thing is. Probably need
a conversation starter to get things
going, make things easier for them. And
if you fill all of those fields out, you
will get one of these GPTs, which in
practice looks like this. And this is
one of the more complex ones that we
have. It's a prompt improver that I
highly recommend, but that's more of a
intermediate workflow. But essentially
all of the custom instructions in the
background, all the knowledge files and
everything I set it up with are at work
here. And practically this one is
designed to improve prompt. So if I tell
it my prompt is write me an email and I
answer some of these follow-up
questions, it will apply everything I
told it in the background to improve
this prompt, which is the single purpose
this GPT serves. Then there you go.
Here's the improved prompt right here.
And this is certainly not a default chat
GPT response right here. The downside of
GPTs is that it doesn't allow you to
group multiple conversations. So, as you
start new chats, it's easy to lose them
in your history over time. And they add
another layer of customization with
custom actions, and you get to select
which tools the GPT has access to,
making them kind of the most advanced
thing that you can do within chat GPT.
Some people prefer GPTs over projects,
but I can tell you I myself in my
day-to-day workflow around 90% of the
time I find myself in one of my two or
three main projects, work context,
personal context, and then often I do
specific projects if I'm working on a
project. And that's really all the level
of conversation customization you have
in chat GPT. And obviously there's also
just adding things to your prompt. These
are just the different ways to help you
out so you don't have to add specific
information every single time. But it
leaves one question open which is how do
these different things interact with
each other. Both custom instructions and
memories are account level. So they
affect every single conversation you
have with chat GPT including the
conversations in projects except
conversations with GPTs. As GPTs serve a
single use case, these are not affected
by your memories and custom
instructions. And that's really it. And
here's what it breaks down to. Use
memories if you're new to chat GPT or
only use it casually, which I would say
is less than five conversations a week.
Then you can graduate to projects which
allow you to separate your work life
from your private life. But in there,
make sure to turn on project based
memories. And if you want to manage the
context for somebody else, GPTs are by
far the best way to do it. For these,
you will need a paid plan, though. And
ultimately, custom instructions are
optional, but if you're using projects
just like I suggested, you don't really
need them. And that's really all the
customization tools in Chat GPT. And in
case you're wondering what are the best
use cases for your particular interest
inside of Chat GPT, I created a one
minute assessment that is going to
recommend a set of prompts that are
guaranteed to be relevant to you cuz
what good is customizing your answers if
you're not even exactly sure what task
Chatt can even do for you? Check that
out in the first link in the
description. And with that being said,
my name is Igor and I hope you have a
wonderful